Carson Bruce

I am passionate about creating simple and beautiful apps.

I plan and deliver throughout the entire software development process, from when a project is imagined to its end as the app is released. I've worked on a number of large projects, demonstrating my experience through a range of roles. I have completed tasks that cover the length and breadth of a project.

My key attributes include: problem solving, speed to learn, open mindedness, being a team player, and communication.

I am a year-zero adopter of JavaScript technologies, Angular, React, Node.js, and Express, embracing the continuing shift towards simpler and more agile systems and process. I am at home working with JavaScript and all the technologies and processes it enables.

Get in touch at hello@carson.kiwi

Experience

Solnet

Aug 2012 - Now (3.5 years)

I started Solnet a week out from graduating kicking off the role straight into the delivery team of the company. A year in I moved on over into the Digital team. I have gained experience with several high profile clients placed first as a developer along with other roles such as devops, ux, team lead, tech lead. More recently in my time at Solnet I have been involved in mentoring others in JavaScript tooling and practices.

Have a look at the following Projects section to see of some of the work I've done at Solnet.

Research Project: Query Expansion

Nov 2011 - March 2012 (4 months)

My second research opportunity was offered by the supervisor of my honours project to further its final report towards an end goal of a published research paper. With some give and take from the wider Web Intelligence team at Victoria I managed to get the paper submitted and accepted to an Australasian Web Intelligence conference by the end of my research.

Research Project: Eye Gaze tracking

Nov 2010 - March 2011 (4 months)

I was awarded a research scholarship at the end of my 300 level university year. With support from my supervisor and his team, I contributed to development of an open source gaze tracking system helping it evolve to a level where it could benefit the university, saving an equivalent commercial product cost of \$10,000. In addition to learning about eye-tracking systems I gained experience in planning and directing a research project and project management.

Cool Bananas

Nov 2009 - March 2010 (4 months)

Interning with a fellow student alongside a senior software engineer I worked on a project developing a prototype scripting parser and runtime for embedded systems. The experience helped cement my years study learning C, Agile processes, and testing practices. The project proved successful gaining further funding being developed into a commercial product.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Software Engineering, First Class Honours

Victoria University of Wellington *2007-2012*

Projects

Employment Agreement Builder

Ministry of Business and Innovation and Employment

EAB is a web application that provides value to front end users and those who maintain the backend. Using the tool, small to medium businesses can step through the process of creating a new Employment agreement while learning about employment law with easy-to-digest content and links. I led the implementation design while teaching a Senior Java developer transitioning to JavaScript. The project met its internal and external objectives and was finished in three months.

- Practiced BDD and TDD development processes ending up with a feature complete automated test suite.
- Created a reusable data-driven forms solution that would support future contract builders for MBIE.
- Helped sell a through and through Javascript solution internally to Solnet and externally to MBIE.
- Went beyond the static wireframes creating my own motion design and micro user interactions.
- Created a Node.js micro services implementation handles 10x expected load on low cost two node cloud infrastructure.
- Created and published a decoupled CMS component to support the application that provided more features than the Javascript CMS landscape at the time.

- Created internal email, document, form components already reused on other projects.
- Created security implementation that sailed through 3rd party security review.
- Implemented a CI environment that performed automated testing and releases a dozen times a day avoid any manual tasks.
- Pushed docker solution handling node scaling, static servers and bringing build and deployment time down to minutes rather than hours.

Online Banking

Westpac

I was part of a Westpac project to rewrite their online banking applications originally rolled in as an IBM Worklight consultant and dev ops engineer. I helped keep the project oiled by mediating communications between developers from API and Client teams. I improved automation in local, development, and test environments, which helped developers become more autonomous providing an interface for logs, deployments, and environment stats. After two months I was promoted to technical lead of a team five large responsible for feature development in the middleware including client security.

- Presented and owned the solutions of several developer tooling and experience improvements.
- Technical leader and mentor of a team five large covering a wide spread of technologies and environments.
- Trusted as the gatekeeper of critical development and test environments relied on by a team 60 large.
- Designed, implemented, and tested a JavaScript middleware framework that improved the abstraction and reliability of the middleware HTTP adapters.
- Designed, implemented, and tested the security feature encompassing the client and middleware layers.
- Presented a UX review noting several usability and performance improvements for the application.
- Worked with a wide spread of technology: Backbone, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jenkins, iOS, Android, Git, Svn, Java, Spring, IBM WebSphere, IBM Worklight, COBOL.

NEON

Sky TV

NEON is Sky TV's entry into the New Zealand TV on demand market. Our project was responsible for implementing the Web client and the Web API supporting other NEON apps sitting on other platforms. My role was a front end developer with a close interest in the Web API and UX layers that my tasks depended on. I was tasked with designing a set of middleware REST API based on a SAAS backend that the client layers would consume. I was also asked to fill gaps in the UX and design that the

static wireframes designed in a separate project did not cover.

- Managed my time effectively within a time critical environment completing and communicating tasks to project managers.
- Designed REST API transforming PAAS data sources to support the multiple client layers
- Collaborated with UX and design teams ensuring good usability of solution.
- Owned and presented UX and design alternatives to client.
- Worked remotely for half the project while still tracking my tasks in good time.

Crew Forms

Air New Zealand

Crew forms was a heavily digital project looking to turn a paper based form into a mobile tablet-based solution. The experience of these forms was improved with the new technology and with a change in platform the forms were allowed to be reimagined through UX process to further better user experience rather than being a clone of the paper solution. I worked on the project in its second phase after its first release bringing in a couple of new features and polishing the first implementation.

- Polished the app correcting dozens of browser rendering bottlenecks resulting in a jank free hybrid solution.
- Worked with UX and design team to best fit solutions with the technology stack.
- Extended the apps feature list and matching test coverage under time.
- Provided a solution to a bug found within the hybrid framework Steroids.js

Name learning game

Private

We entered in a competition to imagine, design, and develop a proof of concept mobile gamification app in 3 days. The brief was to create an educational tool that would help staff learn the names of their clients. Our UX and developer streams worked well together from the start, laying foundations for one another and we managed to create a complete working iOS game that would quiz the user on people's names with multiple mini-games supported by a global leaderboard. We were placed well in the competition winning the prize of placing in the company's evaluation panel for future projects followed shortly after with a winning proposal for a separate project.

- Created a complete proof of concept application in 3 days.
- Succeeded in gaining a position on the client's project panel.
- Worked effectively with other JavaScript, UX and UI developers in parallel streams.

Employee Cost Calculator

The Employee Cost Calculator encourages small to medium sized New Zealand business to hire new employees by estimating how much a new employee will cost them. At the beginning of the project my role was to assist with the RFP document and solution design. Towards the end of the projects I assisted with UAT and PROD handovers and implementing the Analytics feature.

- Created proof of concept application used as pre sales collateral.
- Contributed to the RFP solution design and estimates.
- Researched, designed, and implemented a Google Analytics solution over a weekend.
- Managed app support for UAT test handover.

Public website

Solnet

In a small team with two UI designers we were given the task to redevelop Solnet's website. I had the responsibility to select technologies to best fit our needs choosing a fullstack JavaScript solution with a static file system content source.

- Self managed ourselves and our dependencies in the team avoiding the overheads of a Project manager.
- Owned the tasks of organising content from company.
- Pushed and spoke to technologies from the emerging JavaScript ecosystem

Shared Capability

ACC

Shared capability focused on developing and sharing best practices within a platform of technology to support parallel and future projects. I was exposed to a variety of technology and process including CI, Agile, UX, Testing, Java, IBM, and JavaScript. It was this project that my interest in JavaScript and UX starting spinning, thrilled by the craft and challenge resulting in the difference between something lovable or not.

- Developed a developer's guide supporting other developers using IBM Forms Experience Builder.
- Integrated IBM Forms Experience Builder product with IBM Portal collaborating with IBM development team and providing product defect solutions.

Interests

JavaScript	User Experience	Netball
Running	Cycling	Photography
Gaming	Sound systems	Beer brewing
	Stenciling	

hello@carson.kiwi

GitHub https://github.com/Kauabunga Linkedin https://nz.linkedin.com/in/carsonbruce